Inventory of the Cook-Luttrell Papers 1848-1890
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Tax Receipts. (Box-folder 2:14-17)
  - Cook Family Tax Receipts, 1858-1882. (Folder 14-16)
    - Susan [M.] Cook[e], Culpeper County, Virginia: County tax receipts, 1858-1871., 11 items. (Box-folder 2:14)
    - Thomas Jimson Cook, Culpeper County, Virginia: County tax receipts, 1858-1871., 9 items. (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Luttrell Family: Tax Receipts, 1855-1862., 14 items. (Box-folder 2:17)
    James W. Luttrell, Culpeper County, Virginia: County and state tax receipts, including "Receipt for United States Direct Taxes," 186[4], collected by authority of an Act of Congress passed 7 June 1862, "An Act for the Collection of direct taxes in insurrectionary districts within the United States, and for other purposes."
  Series 4: Legal Documents
- Legal Documents. (Box-folder 2:18-19)
  - Cook Family Legal Documents, 1834-18 [59?]. (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Will of Alfred Cook, 15 May 1834., 2 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Statement of accounts for the estate of William Cooke [sic], deceased; signed by legatees of Elias Cooke, Cecy Cook, William Bywaters, John C. Bywaters, Mitchan Corbin, and Richard H. Bywaters, 30 January 1838., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Copy of a deed of gift between Alfred Cook and his son, Thomas J. Cook, both of Culpeper County, Virginia, 25 May 1842., 2 pages. ACyS of ADS. (Box-folder 2:18)
      Gives Thomas the responsibility for Alfred's farm, stock, and slaves, as well as the schooling of his brother, B[urrell] H. Cook, and sister, Lucy E. Cook; witnessed by Pierce Perry.
    - Agreement between Fanny Dade and Joseph H. Marshal, 12 August 1857., 2 pages. ACyS of ADS. (Box-folder 2:18)
      A copy of "An Agreement...between Fanny Dade a free woman of colour of the County of Culpeper and the State of Virginia...and Joseph H. Marshal of the County of Saline and the state of Missouri" for the indenture of her two sons, George Henry and John Richard; witnessed by Thomas J. Cooke [sic].
    - Grant of land from Alfred Cook and Susan S. Cook to William A. Cook, Thomas J. Cook, and Burrell H. Cook, October [ante 1859]., 2 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Luttrell Family Legal Documents, 1859-1896., 4 items. (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Statement giving James W. Luttrell permission to claim land in the name of Alfred Cook, 1859., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:19)
      Statement giving James W. Luttrell permission to claim land in the name of Alfred Cook, deceased, that it might be sold for the benefit of his heirs; contains signatures of heirs.
    - Receipt for deed entered by Virginia T. Corbin and Sylvester M. Corbin, Culpeper County, Virginia, Reverse endorsed to J.W. Luttrell, 1860., 2 pages. PDS. (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Certificate appointing James W. Luttrell as surveyor of roads for Culpeper County, Virginia, 19 April 1876., 2 pages. PDS. (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Mary E. Luttrell, [Amissville, Virginia], administratrix: Financial receipts from Mutual Fire Insurance County, Loudoun County, Virginia, 1895-1896., 2 items. (Box-folder 2:19)
  Series 5: Miscellaneous Papers
- Miscellaneous Papers. (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Correspondence, 1852-1871., 3 items. (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Amanda C. Marshall, n.p., to "friend" [?], n.p., 13 July 1852., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:1)
      Tells family news and of frequency of illness; asks after friends and family; apologizes for taking so long to write back.
    - H.R. Bywaters, Carthage, Ohio, to "Aunt" [?], n.p., 8 August 1871., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:1)
      Announces the death of his mother; mentions having heard from Missouri relatives.
    - L.H. [Shoben?], n.p., to "Miss" Peale, n.p., 24 December n.y., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:1)
      Note to accompany Christmas gift; mentions also "Miss" Washington.
  - Business Accounts, Correspondence, Receipts, 1829-1878. (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Sallie Bywaters, [Oak Shade], Culpeper County, Virginia: Financial receipts for food and dry goods, 6 February 1862 - 21 January 1878., 7 items. (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Sarah Bywaters, [Culpeper County, Virginia]: Financial receipts for food and dry goods purchased, 15 October 1829 - 24 January 1864., 7 items. (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Thomas Bywaters, Jeffersonton, [Virginia]: Financial receipt, 19 December 1832., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Miscellaneous accounts, 1855-1876., 12 items. (Box-folder 3:2)
      Persons of note include Jakson Kines, James Mazingo, J.W. Corbin, Payne V. Baker, W.H. Perry, John Jett, George L. Pazne, and Turner L. Jones.
  - Tax Receipts (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Armistead Banks, Culpeper County, Virginia: Tax Receipts, 1879, 1881., 2 items. PDsS. (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Kitty Bywaters, [Culpeper County, Virginia]: Tax receipts, 1842, 1848., 2 items. PDsS. (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Sarah Bywaters, Culpeper County, [Virginia]: County tax receipts, 1873-1881., 7 items. (Box-folder 3:3)
      Many have notation "sold to Jas. W. Luttrell for taxes."
  - Poetry, 1853 and n.d. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - [?], Waterloo, [Virginia], At the Sabbath School, 31 June 1853., 1 page. AMs. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Dublin Bay, by Josie A. Goodwin, n.d., 2 pages. AMsS. frag. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Farewell, n.d., 2 pages. M. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - I Feel Tis Time to Part, poem signed by "Ernest" [?], n.d., 2 pages. AMS. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - I'm Not Ashamed to Own My Lord, unsigned poem, n.d., 2 pages. AMs. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - A Place in [?] Memory Dearest, poem signed by Mollie [Luttrell?], n.d., 2 pages. AMsS. (Box-folder 3:4)
    - A Sketch of a Sermon by Rev[eren]d Jno. [John] Smith, from 1st Peter..., n.d, 4 pages. AMs. (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Other. (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Lace pattern [?], n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Lodging accounts [?], n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Receipt [sic] [recipe] for Colouring yarn, from J. [?] G. Miller, n.p., n.d., 1 item. ALS. (Box-folder 3:6)
    - School Related Materials, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:5)
      - Rule for Using the Protractor, n.d. (Box-folder 3:5)
      - Writing Practice by Richard Y. Luttrell, n.d. (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Envelopes. (Box-folder 3:6)